<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_GB" /><updated>2018-02-18T18:03:02+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/</id><title type="html">Mind the Gaps</title><subtitle>Mind the Gaps is a thought provoking **experiment** to bring citizen sensing closer to policy making. It is a **system** for open data collection about well-being and inequalities in cities.

It will invite citizens to **paint a more comprehensive picture** of their experience of their neighbourhood.

It adds qualitative and granular data to existing robust datasets.
This will aim to stimulate open discussions and help policy makers build more resilient cities.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Retrospective of the day</title><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/14/retrospective.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retrospective of the day" /><published>2018-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/14/retrospective</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/14/retrospective.html">&lt;p&gt;Here are the questions we asked to ourselves after the end of the day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What did you enjoy the most today?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would you like to change tomorrow?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there something slowing you down?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-14-st-werburghs.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-14-st-werburghs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;enjoy&quot;&gt;Enjoy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;discovering even more neighbourhoods in Bristol (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;major heart love for the Folk House and the St Rbrhrg Community Centre (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;experiencing outreach and face to face interviews first hand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;getting Phil’s always valuable feedback on local authorities (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;having a better understanding of barriers and challenges in accessing all communities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoyed speaking to a member of the homeless community–it’s a huge problem that everyone brings up so it’s nice to get their point of view too&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoyed planning next week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoyed iterating the form as we tried it with respondants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like crossing the various layers of the city from Clifton, to Bristol Castle then Easton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoyed that Alaine took the time to grab some bread.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like seing people aswering the form and being surprised that it was that easy and quick (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am proud that we were able to go from semi directed interviews to an online version in 1 day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I liked seing the diversity of the people in the place we visited and their interactions too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-14-train.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-14-train.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;to-change&quot;&gt;To change&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it was more challenging for me than the other days–I got caught up in the complexity of the project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I find value in everything we do but I feel I lack individual time to invest in our natural skill set (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;more time (dream change)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we have a structure that works–it results in a productive way so we should keep it every day (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I would like to  be able to reflect more when responding in a stresfull situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;slowing-me-down&quot;&gt;Slowing me down&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;doubts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unpredictability of locating communities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bad quality of not being able to recover during the night, because of sleep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="retrospective" /><summary type="html">Here are the questions we asked to ourselves after the end of the day:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://mind-the-gaps.org/assets/posts/2018-02-14-st-werburghs.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Retrospective of the day</title><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/13/retrospective.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retrospective of the day" /><published>2018-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/13/retrospective</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/13/retrospective.html">&lt;p&gt;Here are the questions we asked to ourselves after the end of the day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What did you enjoy the most today?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would you like to change tomorrow?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there something slowing you down?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-13-interviews-debrief.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-13-interviews-debrief.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;enjoy&quot;&gt;Enjoy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;getting out on the field (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;testing, reworking, testing, reworking (+2)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it’s nice to be back in Bristol (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my leap into street interviewing (first time)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;happy to share my fears with others and that you were okay to accomodate them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I really enjoyed hot toddy cure from the cold weather (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoyed the team dynamics today–I felt we were less confused than yesterday and maybe some other days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoyed a day without stress and collecting such an output in such a short amount of time and with no pre-plan (24 interviews!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoyed hearing from Bristolians about the quality of life, straight from the horse’s mouth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoyed our transition to prototyping. Materialising our work after having found the right thing to build. It’s a comforting feeling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoy Alaine’s skills for getting us out on the field.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoyed seeing team members interviewing and able to bounce back.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I loved the cooking sessions today. (+2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-13-lunch.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-13-lunch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;to-change&quot;&gt;To change&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to work at a faster pace–we had a very good pace the first week we came here&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to work on something of a digital nature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;slowing-me-down&quot;&gt;Slowing me down&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;not enough energy (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lack of chocolate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;other-comments&quot;&gt;Other comments&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;turning the interviews into data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cross-referencing our questions with those of the quality of life survey to ensure we are adding value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="retrospective" /><summary type="html">Here are the questions we asked to ourselves after the end of the day:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://mind-the-gaps.org/assets/posts/2018-02-13-interviews-debrief.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guerilla interviews (afternoon session)</title><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/13/interviews-pm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guerilla interviews (afternoon session)" /><published>2018-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/13/interviews-pm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/13/interviews-pm.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;places-interviewed&quot;&gt;Places interviewed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clifton Down area (Sainsbury’s arcades, street, bus stops).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;interview-questions&quot;&gt;Interview questions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you live in Bristol?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you like the city?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you tell me a bit more about why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do you have enough time time to do the things you want?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you had more time what would you do with it?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transport
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How do you get around?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Why?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;House/Home
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;How long have you been living there?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What do you like about your home?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do have any plans to change you home?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whereabouts do you live?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;respondants&quot;&gt;Respondants&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-1&quot;&gt;Respondant 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you live in Bristol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you like the city?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’m still here. There are better places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So you don’t like it.
Yes, it’s okay,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell me a bit more about why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Well actually &lt;em&gt;no I don’t like it&lt;/em&gt;. The biggest problem is public transport. It’s too expensive. And there are no alternative. There is way too much traffic in the street. And it’s on the way  of the bus.
Also, buses are very infrequent. The bus are privatised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Council said they would do things. But it’s always empty promises.
In Cardiff they have an International Stadium. Both cities are similar size but Bristol has nothing of similar calibre.
Plymouth has a football playground and an ice rink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Standing here I can see 4 cafes. There are too many. I don’t understand it.
Housing is taking over. Plus bars and cafe. But there are no more schools, doctors and hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example the pub at the end of the road. It is turned into 15 flats. Where is the infrastructure. It equals at least 10 cars. And that’s only one development, on one street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally the Council Tax. It is not good value. He has no kids. And the only things he think he gets are police officers. At least, the last mayor had a plan. The current mayor has kind of disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The political correctness of the city. Because of the history of the city, because we are not proud of it. They are changing the name of places… it does not change history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably after I leave (this interview), I’ll think about the good things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have enough time time to do the things you want?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you had more time what would you do with it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Actually, I want to talk about council tax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;: ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-2&quot;&gt;Respondant 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you live in Bristol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you like the city.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes I do. I moved here for uni. And it’s great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell me more?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not really. I go to uni. I have my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you like in the city out of uni?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now I’m on my way to meet some friends. We are members of a running club. I’m also taking driving lessons. It’s probably a good place to learn how to drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it a house or a home?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like it. Mostly because of the people I live with. But also thanks to the layout of the flat makes it great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have plans to change?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes. Next year I’m moving out because my course will be somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;: ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-3&quot;&gt;Respondant 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you like the city?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s a great size. Good mix of people. It feels international.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A lot of people say there is a lot going on, can you tell me more?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes. There are tons of bars and restaurants. So there is always something new to try. Galleries and exhibitions, culture and festivals, music and otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transport&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you get around the city?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I cycle now. I’m new to it. Because the bus was not great.
The train is good but limited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find cycling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s good. The city is a nice size for it. There are cycle lanes. But they stop suddenly. There also a lot of dual footpaths and cycle lanes which is really annoying. Pedestrians get annoyed but at the end of the day it is still a cycle lane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;: ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-4&quot;&gt;Respondant 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you live in Bristol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you like the city?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I like it a lot. There is lot going on. The countryside is very accessible. I was born here. I moved back here from London when my kids became teenager. I thought it would be a good place for them to spend years. Also, it has a lot of beautiful places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have enough time to do the things you want?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Visit more places in the city. More exercise. Healthy things and I would like to make time in my life for old friends. Actually, old friends and new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell me more about the visit places in the city?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The old houses and historic places. I’d like to learn more an experience rather than the history of the city. And the different cultures of the different areas. I don’t know if you notices but places are very separate. It is a very divided city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been living here for 50 years. And it has not changed one bit. When I moved back I was surprised it was still like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transport&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you get around?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I walk and take the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’m still trying to find the courage to drive. I guess it comes down to cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is that walking is cheaper than taking the bus?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now, it’s just that walking and taking the bus is cheaper than taking the taxi. The bus is awful. It is very expensive. And infrequent. The local trains however are really good, affordable but limited in terms of route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you been there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
12 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you feel secure in your home? Inside and outside?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like about your home?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s big! I have a garden. It’s quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any plans to change your home?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Unfortunately I am going through a separation. So plan A is to stay and to rent out a room. Plan B is to move out and find something smaller. I’d rather stay. Mostly because how secure it is. And neighbours are lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;: Cotham&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-5&quot;&gt;Respondant 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you live in Bristol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No but I live right outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like about Bristol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Live music. There is a lot going on but it’s not too big. Art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transport&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cycle because it’s cheap and quicker. Where I live, roads are flat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you use alternative ways of transport?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buses are too expensive and don’t run late enough to where I live. And it does not reflect the fact that Bristol likes to think of itself as an encouraging city.
I take the train, it’s cheaper and more reliable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What changes would you make to improve your transportation options?
Cycling lanes. Bristol does not live up to the standard of a green capital. It is not cycling friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;: Shirehampton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-6&quot;&gt;Respondant 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you live in Bristol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I like it’s not too big. But is has everything we need. I’m a parent of three. So parks, shops, nurseries and schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How long have you lived here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s conveniently located: I can walk to work. I use the car to get away from the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you planning to make any changes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes we’ve work going at the moment, building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you improve?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
More battery cars. Make roads electric only. Make bikes priority. The air quality is bad. There is too much pollution. We live in the city centre and with small children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;: St Andrews&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-7&quot;&gt;Respondant 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you live in Bristol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The diversity of cultures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transport&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bus and train. I don’t want and don’t need a car so I don’t own one. Same for the bike.
I am well connected to transportation routes. I usually take the train to go to work in Avonmouth. I would like it to be more reliable. Sometimes trains are cancelled.
I buy my weekly train ticket on the train. And it costs £6. Buses are way too expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;: Clifton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-8&quot;&gt;Respondant 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you live in Bristol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I can do sports. Like football.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transport&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to take one or multiple buses to get to work. Sometimes they are late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you like to change about this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
What? That’s a strange question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;: Easton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-9&quot;&gt;Respondant 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you live in Bristol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes. I have been here 9 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There is always stuff going on. It’s busy but not London busy. I like to go out for entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you feel you have enough time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No. Work takes 90% of my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you had extra time, what would you do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Spend time with loved ones. They live in Wales. Or maybe, enroll in a college course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is that something you thought of through work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No, I have never really thought of that? As I said, I work to 8:30 to 6pm so there is little time for something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;: ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-10&quot;&gt;Respondant 10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you live in Bristol?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you like the city?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I like concerts, cinema, interesting nightlife and a variety of bars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have enough time time to do the things you want?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not enough time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do you feel you lack time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I like space near me, spaces to make things, such as space to carve stone. I need to travel to this. The real estate prices are too high to allow these kinds of spaces in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;: Totterdown&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="bristol" /><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html">Places interviewed</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guerilla interviews (morning session)</title><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/13/interviews-am.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guerilla interviews (morning session)" /><published>2018-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/13/interviews-am</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/13/interviews-am.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;places-interviewed&quot;&gt;Places interviewed&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bristol Temple Meads, by We the Curious, on the Watershed promenade…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;interview-questions&quot;&gt;Interview questions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you like it there? What do you like?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there anything you’d change? Any improvements that would make your life better?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional: Transport / home / food&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;respondants&quot;&gt;Respondants&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-1&quot;&gt;Respondant 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Keynsham&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you like it there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yep it’s OK, It’s fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you like about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I don’t know really. It’s good. It’s close to family and friends. The location is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It is easy to get in and out off. Easy to get into Bristol and get out to the countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any issues there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No, no issues&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any improvements that would make your life better?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-2&quot;&gt;Respondant 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bishopston, I’ve lived in my home for twenty years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you feel about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s nice. If I had to move, I would really miss my area. I can’t think of anywhere better to go. You should come see for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s nice about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s close to Gloucester Road, there are lots of independent shops, the community there is very friendly. I spent two months in Australia recently and my neighbours took care of my place here, there’s good trust. We look out for each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you’d change? Any improvements that would make your life better?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Car parking on the pavement, car parking in general is a problem. There’s only one parking space per house but some houses need to accomodate more than one car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are the transport links ok, would this solve the problem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The transport’s ok but it’s not enough to no longer need a car. Improvements would be great, but people need incentive to not use their cars. I recently was eligible for a senior citizen card which makes transport free and I haven’t used my car as much since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-3&quot;&gt;Respondant 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Horfield&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you feel about your neighbourhood&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I quite like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I never really thought about it before. It’s a bit far out but still walkable, which is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you enjoy about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I don’t use many of the facilities there. — Long pause — There are nice pubs and I suppose the facilities are reasonable, it’s on a main bus route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any issues?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I live on a main road and the bus stops close to my house. My wife would say the council estate across the road is a problem, but it doesn’t bother me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is pollution an issue for you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Apart from the noise and the safety risk from the traffic, not really. My area is not that bad in terms of pollution. It’s no worse than in any city. You can’t live in a city and expected non-polluted air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you’d like to add.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hmmmmmm… Ultimately, it’s depressing. The students accomodation on mass, the cramming in of students — landlords buy up all the houses and add annexes to cram as many in as possible. Every two years, the residents change, maybe they’re nice, maybe they’re not. Sometimes they turn their music off at midnight, sometimes they have 24 hour parties and shout in the street at 7am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the influx of students affect your ability to form relationships with the community?
Hmm. I have my friends, I know the name of my next door neighbours, and that’s it. Apart from baby groups, they add to it. It is a barrier to forming a community, but because I have my own friends, it doesn’t affect me. There are a lot of community halls around, I have no real need for them but they’re important for kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-4&quot;&gt;Respondant 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Melbourne&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you enjoy there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s safe and calm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently looking for a job to earn money and find another place to live. I live with my sister at the moment. I’ve moved to Bristol recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you look for if you were to move elsewhere?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The price. I want to save money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your plans with that goal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It helps to feel secure, to feel like you have a security net, a buffer. Stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the things that would turn you down?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fights in the street, thugs. I wouldn’t feel safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What could be done to improve that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Police around. It makes me feel safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-5&quot;&gt;Respondant 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which neighborhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hambrew - St Andrews&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a fine for smoking on the street and put my cigarette butt in a proper litter bin but it fell and he got fined. I would have preferred a warning instead of a fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I like here is that people are nice, it’s calm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is that important to you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I feel safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you enjoy less there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Somalians in the street by night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why by night?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
They’re trying to earn money, by selling drugs or stealing money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think could be an improvement on that subject?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That they get punished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Would there be any other solution?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-6&quot;&gt;Respondant 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Kingswood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you like living there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, it’s convenient. There is a supermarket really close to my house. There are good bus journeys. And there is a Pizza Hut next door, and it’s pretty cool. I have been living here for 12 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have anything to add?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I love Bristol. And if i did not live here, I would like to move here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you would change or improve?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It is a little messy. There is a lot of rubbish flying around. The Kingswood shopping centre closed down so it looks abandoned. And it can be a bit dangerous because of the wood planks lying around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you would add?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Homeless people. There a lot of them. How can we go and change that? ‘Cause you can’t really help them.
Drug use is also a problem. Particularly in parks. In Eastville or Castle Park for instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-7&quot;&gt;Respondant 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
St Werburghs – it’s close to St Paul’s. It’s rough and I got robbed there. But I can walk through Montpellier which is nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you like living there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes, it’s pretty alternative. It has a farm. And there are a lot of communities. They have fairs at the farm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is transport in your area?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There is only 1 bus which goes to Bishopston Station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you feel about your home?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There is a little back passage way. It is a little scary. It’s not like in Clifton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What could be done to improve your life here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You could do more about homelessness and drug dealers. We can’t do anything about it. It needs to come from higher up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are the food options next to her house?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There is a Tesco and it’s perfectly convenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-8&quot;&gt;Respondant 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Kingswood – we’ve only been there recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you like it there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
She used to live in Whitehall. Which is very trendy. Kingswood is a bit more working class if you know what I mean. It is not as familiar. Whitehall was multicultural; food and people from different places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you would change?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
They live by a busy road. And the playground is not as nice for children for example. In Easton there was an adventure playground that was much better. Out there it is a little scruffy.
I’m on the border of Bristol and South Gloucester. It has a vibrant center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-9&quot;&gt;Respondant 9&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Temple Meads&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you enjoy living there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You can walk into town. And it’s close to the train station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you would change?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It needs a shop. All the shops are miles away. It’s an up and coming area. There is a lot of change. But it would be nice to have a shop. And more green areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-10&quot;&gt;Respondant 10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Whitechurch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you enjoy there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not much, it has a nice community. It’s close to the countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you tell me more about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Good connection to the centre, nice transportation options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you change?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’d like to live closer to town. I spend a lot of time there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you improve about transport?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The cost. I would like to have more bus route options, where I live there’s only one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-11&quot;&gt;Respondant 11&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Harbourside&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do you enjoy living there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Close to the river, it has coffee shops. It’s nice. I like nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Would you change anything?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any improvements you would like to see in the area?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
More development in the area, more shops and cafes. It would be more fun. Now I have to go to the city centre to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-12&quot;&gt;Respondant 12&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Kingswood&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do you like living there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s quiet, friendly, clean and it feels safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can take my dog out with a leash and it’s super nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you dislike about the area?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The hills, but I can’t do much about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would it change if it wasn’t that hilly?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I would walk more and would use my car a bit less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Would you change anything?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not really, streets are clean, teams of volunteers clean the streets once a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-13&quot;&gt;Respondant 13&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Easton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do you like it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sweet mart. It’s an organic food store. They have everything from everywhere, it’s close to my friends, it’s healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s close the centre, it’s cheap, it’s good value for money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is that important for you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I can travel more. I keep exploring and can understand different cultures…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you dislike in the area?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Theft. I don’t leave my window open because people rob. It didn’t happen to me, but I heard about it. If it happened to me, it would cost a lot because I don’t have insurance. I keep it low profile so I don’t have to get an insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What would you like to see improve in the area?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Nothing, it’s nice as it is, it’s diverse and multicultural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;respondant-14&quot;&gt;Respondant 14&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What neighbourhood do you live in?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
St. George (2 years)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you enjoy about it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My son was born there and I had access to tones of mom and baby groups. There is a strong sense of community and the parks and really useful as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything you’d change?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Not really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are your transport options there?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yep there are great busses but they could be cheaper. I cycle to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How about the food options?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
They are great. We shop at Aldi and Lidl for the low prices but we also shop at a deli where we get organic food and dairy alternatives because I have a lot of allergies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there anything that could improve her life here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I could use a little bit more money. I work 12 hrs per week because I take care of my child. My husband earns good money. He is a carpenter, so he is self employed. I few weeks ago we all had a bad cold and he doesn’t get any sick pay or holiday pay so if I could change anything I would like self employed people to get sick pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusions&quot;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;positives&quot;&gt;Positives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;q&gt;What do you like about your area?&lt;/q&gt; is a nice opener.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had better results when people were sitting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First time around doing guerrilla interviews in the street for some team members, went well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open questions, open results — positive and negative: it was not leading at all, but people could sometimes have benefitted from prompts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Handy to discover the vocabulary of concerns straight from citizens mouths.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It was quite relaxed, for people and for us.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘What is / how is that important for you?’ is a question that enabled us to go more in depth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-improve&quot;&gt;To improve&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diverse responses, hard to draw conclusions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It was harder to ask questions about problems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It felt a little short, which means we didn’t get enough in the tissue of issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People struggled with the lack of structure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Do you enjoy your area?’ didn’t yield a lot of results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Question vertigo: we could explore topics more in depth / offer prompts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It captures safety/comfort issues well but it feels incomplete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doubts-or-ideas&quot;&gt;Doubts or ideas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The interviews were sometimes very short&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unsure about the replicability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unsure about the sample selection, but at this stage, is there something we need to worry about?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We could do with more direct questions about topics. Like ‘what would be helpful about &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;topic&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;?’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would like to see a reaction to a digital form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Re-align on what we are hoping to achieve / get out of these preliminary interviews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visibility on our next steps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bias in favor of your neighbourhood which makes you want to be more positive about it. Same about the city, city pride.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="bristol" /><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html">Places interviewed Bristol Temple Meads, by We the Curious, on the Watershed promenade…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retrospective of the day</title><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/12/retrospective.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retrospective of the day" /><published>2018-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/12/retrospective</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/12/retrospective.html">&lt;p&gt;Here are the questions we asked to ourselves after the end of the day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What did you enjoy the most today?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would you like to change tomorrow?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there something slowing you down?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;enjoy&quot;&gt;Enjoy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;our collective planning that resulted in a really productive session of external communications (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learning about the thick+thin data (+2)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;discovering that tech ethnography is a thing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;walking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;finding our way through survey questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;watching Tricia Wang TedTalk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cooking at home for lunch (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;writing emails to keep stakeholders up to date&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;getting in touch with new people and getting prompt responses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when we discarded writing questions so as we avoid putting our bias in the survey prototype&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the &lt;em&gt;aha&lt;/em&gt; moment on the way back from the cafe, which combines the newly discovered thick data ethnography process and quantitative data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-12-planning.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-12-planning.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;to-change&quot;&gt;To change&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;communicate visually a bit more&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;try to balance caveats and criticism with counter offers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to reflect more before snapping a prompt and harsh comment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to ask “are we done yet?” when I feel lost instead of backtracking the conversation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;felt uncomfortable about my communication when we decided not to write the questions–we did not end up doing what we planned; wrapping up the session will help next time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-12-designing-questions.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-12-designing-questions.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;slowing-me-down&quot;&gt;Slowing me down&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ability to communicate ideas clearly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the lack of deep sleep of the previous days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the feeling of time going quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="retrospective" /><summary type="html">Here are the questions we asked to ourselves after the end of the day:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://mind-the-gaps.org/assets/posts/2018-02-12-planning.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ODI Presentation • Jan26-Feb9 in Review</title><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/09/odi-presentation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ODI Presentation • Jan26-Feb9 in Review" /><published>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/09/odi-presentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/09/odi-presentation.html">&lt;p&gt;📄 &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/ODI%20Presentation%20-%20Jan26-Feb09.pdf&quot;&gt;Download the presentation&lt;/a&gt; (PDF document, ~380KB)&lt;br /&gt;
🗣 &lt;a href=&quot;#odi-insights&quot;&gt;Jump to the &lt;em&gt;ODI insights&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-01.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for attending this presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a summary of the past two weeks of work we have done on the &lt;em&gt;Mind the Gaps&lt;/em&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates will be related to the website updates, re-establishing a connection with Bordeaux as well as how we defined the Product and our Methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-02.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made major changes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://dtc-innovation.github.io/mind-the-gaps/&quot;&gt;Mind the Gaps website&lt;/a&gt;. The home categorizes our work in various sections: Latest updates, Insights, Interviews, Workshops, Diary and Team Retrospectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We added &lt;strong&gt;2 new interviews&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://dtc-innovation.github.io/mind-the-gaps/2018/01/19/Interview-John-Kellas.html&quot;&gt;John from the Bristol Health Partners&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&quot;https://dtc-innovation.github.io/mind-the-gaps/2018/01/19/Interview-Patricia-Holley.html&quot;&gt;Patricia from the Jean Golding Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We designed a &lt;strong&gt;mindmap&lt;/strong&gt; which starts from the initial project ideas and develops into 3 main axis of exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We listed &lt;strong&gt;project inspirations&lt;/strong&gt;: visual inspirations but also in term of well-being and quality of life surveys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-03.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map depicts the initial start of the project: visualising inequalities in French and British cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research week unfolds our findings and connects them to the second idea of the project: &lt;strong&gt;citizen sensing&lt;/strong&gt;. We refine this idea to make it more comparable across France and UK but also in term of &lt;em&gt;gaps&lt;/em&gt;, where they are, in term of challenges, communication and &lt;strong&gt;lack of soft and qualitative data&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-04.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-04.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a very good phone call with a Bordeaux councillor.
We also got a chat with the company which provides and designs the Bordeaux Ward diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-05.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-05.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First conclusion is the diagnosis is very little used in the ward we phoned. Mostly because the population increased quickly. The diagnosis is already outdated and thus, is not accurate with issues, concerns and figures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s okay because 4 systems are in use to keep in touch with citizens:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;direct contact (by phone, city hall antenna)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;local council, driven by a 40 people working group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://participation.bordeaux-metropole.fr/&quot;&gt;theme based concertations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;proximity ambassadors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter walk the street and talk to people to get a feeling about what is going on. It is rather unique to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will have a more detailed phone call to know more about how they work,
and how the other wards deal with similar issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-06.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-06.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bordeaux and Bristol are similar and varies at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dealing with deprivation is a mayor priority in Bristol whereas in Bordeaux, this is (re)enforced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/affichTexte.do?cidTexte=JORFTEXT000028636804&amp;amp;categorieLien=id&quot;&gt;2014 loi de programmation pour la ville et la cohésion urbaine&lt;/a&gt; and City Hall &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bordeaux.fr/p84376/pacte-de-cohesion-sociale-et-territoriale&quot;&gt;pacte de cohésion sociale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bristol embraces community-led actions whereas Bordeaux is subject to its city-led working groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well-being is mesured with the quality of life survey in Bristol whereas Bordeaux has its Ward Diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both cities face the same problems (Housing, Transport, Jobs, Costs of living, etc.) and ought to to be a leading &lt;em&gt;smart city&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-07.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-07.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sketched a lot of our ideas on paper, prototyped an online form and explored what it would look like as an offline artefact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-08.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-08.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring survey themes and form controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-09.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-09.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring the use of postcards to collect informations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-10.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring a more conversational approach to form controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-11.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-11.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring a more conversational approach with an online form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-12.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-12.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is this moment again when we refine what we think the project is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-13.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-13.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind the Gaps is a thought provoking experiment to bring citizen sensing closer to policy making. It is &lt;strong&gt;a system for open data collection about well-being and inequalities in cities&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will invite citizens to paint a more comprehensive picture of their experience of their neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It complements existing robust datasets with qualitative and granular datapoints. This will aim &lt;strong&gt;to stimulate open discussions&lt;/strong&gt; and help policy makers build more resilient cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-14.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-14.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think the project as a &lt;em&gt;toolbox&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;data&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;an online+offline form to collect well-being informations&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;a map of what people express&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;a view to inform&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;methodology&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;to design conversational well-being surveys&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;to run workshops&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;workshops&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;communities run workshops at meetups&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;community groups run workshops&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;salons for councillors and citizens&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;hackathons to use data in other systems&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-15.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-15.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is web based.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website contains the online questionnaire, offline versions of it, a live feed of the data and links to raw datasets as well as a visual map of the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We test this in Bristol (Feb 2018) and Bordeaux (prior to June 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-16.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-16.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-17.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-17.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By testing in Bristol and Bordeaux we will be able to surface cultural differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It provides a free toolbox to run your own surveys about wellbeing and quality of life (as opposed to consultancies).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It adds to the data that is currently collected to inform &lt;em&gt;smart cities&lt;/em&gt;: how can we foster a people-focused approach?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its granularity will create rich data sets that avoid the &lt;em&gt;average&lt;/em&gt; pitfall in statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is complementary to existing quantitive data sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-18.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-18.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a way for citizens to collect and access data that is not currently available to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will give people a new opportunity to express their feelings about their neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data set will allow citizens to connect and mobilise under the things that matter the most in their area. A way to express their ‘user needs’ as citizens.
It engages the public with the value of data and specifically open data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-19.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-19.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It highlights the value of citizen sensing to Local Government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It provides the Local Government with a layer of human or qualitative data that they don’t currently have access to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provide a live or more up to date data set for them, useful in fast-evolving trends or areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can surface potential issues and can help address priorities to face challenges in budget cuts across the public sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long term will help instigate a cultural shift within City Halls leading them to trust citizen collected data and release more decision making power to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;odi-insights&quot;&gt;ODI insights&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentation at UK/France Open data Summit 
Stakeholders from France and the UK interested in data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workshop proposal the Data for development festival - to be determined.
Bristol could be a replacement for the display in the Data dome mentioned in the contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thick versus thin data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the best way to collect this information - face to face, best community engagement method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar and complementary to other programs run within the ODI - Service design in local authorities,
Designing in the open. Data ethics canvas. Ecosystem mapping visual language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of internal advocacy and finding the right people when working within local authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should document our research practice and methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of open technology is that it’s not an authority, it’s living and adaptable.
There’s something quite political about the project not being ‘final’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mind the Gaps toolkit could also have a physical component. People are often attracted to that.
Integrate people’s feedback on the toolkit: what is the best way to collect this information?
The most effective being face to face communication, then trickling down to independently run surveys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind the Gaps could also offer interventions for workshops - running your data.
Imagine ways to enable public conversation - reminiscent of Rebecca Ross’s project &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.londonischanging.org/&quot;&gt;London is changing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Branding: explaining what citizen sensing is.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="presentation" /><summary type="html">📄 Download the presentation (PDF document, ~380KB) 🗣 Jump to the ODI insights</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://mind-the-gaps.org/assets/presentations/2018-02-08-odi/slide-14.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An online and offline toolbox to measure well-being in cities</title><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/toolbox.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An online and offline toolbox to measure well-being in cities" /><published>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/toolbox</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/toolbox.html">&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-08-mind-the-gaps-flow.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-08-mind-the-gaps-flow.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-08-mind-the-gaps-ecosystem.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-08-mind-the-gaps-ecosystem.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="workshop" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://mind-the-gaps.org/assets/posts/2018-02-08-mind-the-gaps-flow.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Retrospective of the day</title><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/retrospective.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retrospective of the day" /><published>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/retrospective</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/retrospective.html">&lt;p&gt;Here are the questions we asked to ourselves after the end of the day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What did you enjoy the most today?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would you like to change tomorrow?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there something slowing you down?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-08-sketching.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-08-sketching.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;enjoy&quot;&gt;Enjoy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;asking ourselves the hard questions about what is the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; prototype&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;working at Look Mum No Hands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;all the discovery about data around Wellbeing and quality of life (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the sketching session (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cowriting in the morning (Mind the Gaps is…)(+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the conversations with the people in Bordeaux (+1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;our working process is working&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;getting that sense of validation from the outside world that we are moving in the right direction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phil’s response gave me great ease while creating the survey questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the Typeform trial with branched flows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-08-toolbox.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2018-02-08-toolbox.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;to-change&quot;&gt;To change&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the afternoon alignment was effortful and next time, I’d like to get my hands dirty sooner (trying Typeform etc.)(+1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;slowing-me-down&quot;&gt;Slowing me down&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lack of time!!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the complexity of the issue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="retrospective" /><summary type="html">Here are the questions we asked to ourselves after the end of the day:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mind the Gaps is…</title><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/mind-the-gaps-is.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mind the Gaps is…" /><published>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/mind-the-gaps-is</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/mind-the-gaps-is.html">&lt;p&gt;The intent of this workshop was to ideate around the goals, the meaning and the representation of what &lt;em&gt;Mind the Gaps&lt;/em&gt; is for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works by one of us starting the sentence by “Mind the Gaps is…” and by saying a word. The person next to them would say another word, and so until someone says “fullstop”.
When it happens, the sentence is considered as &lt;em&gt;finished&lt;/em&gt; and we start a new round of collaborative ideation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a framework to understand discrepencies between feelings of citizens and policy makers #democracy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a system to collect, visualise and educate citizens and local governments about data and its complexities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a sensitive approach to data commons which incorporates citizen sensing, open data and a mindful understanding of well-being in the cithey #babam!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then listed 3 words we found representative what &lt;em&gt;Mind the Gaps&lt;/em&gt; is about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;thought provoking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;inform&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;engaging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;co-design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;people focused&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;politically sensitive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cold data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;invisible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;resilience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bounced on these words to write several &lt;em&gt;one liners&lt;/em&gt;. We then collated our trials into the following and satisfying description of the project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Mind the Gaps is a thought provoking &lt;em&gt;experiment&lt;/em&gt; to bring citizen sensing closer to policy making. It is a &lt;em&gt;system&lt;/em&gt; for open data collection about well-being and inequalities in cities.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It will invite citizens to paint a more comprehensive picture of their experience of their neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It adds qualitative and granular data to existing robust datasets.
This will aim to stimulate open discussions and help policy makers build more resilient cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="workshop" /><summary type="html">The intent of this workshop was to ideate around the goals, the meaning and the representation of what Mind the Gaps is for us.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conversational surveys sketching</title><link href="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/conversational-surveys.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conversational surveys sketching" /><published>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/conversational-surveys</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://mind-the-gaps.org/2018/02/08/conversational-surveys.html">&lt;p&gt;The intent of this workshop was to visualise and share what he had in mind
when we were saying the word &lt;em&gt;survey&lt;/em&gt; as of the Mind the Gaps toolbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-alaine.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-alaine.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-postcard-alaine.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-postcard-alaine.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-noemie.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-noemie.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-commute-thomas.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-commute-thomas.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-home-thomas.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-home-thomas.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-time-thomas.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-time-thomas.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="workshop" /><summary type="html">The intent of this workshop was to visualise and share what he had in mind when we were saying the word survey as of the Mind the Gaps toolbox.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://mind-the-gaps.org/assets/workshops/2018-02-08-survey/survey-noemie.png" /></entry></feed>